esslinger.com 2017-07-08

# Privacy Policy

Effective Date May 22, 2017 

Esslinger & Co. Inc.  
1165 Medallion Dr  
Saint Paul, MN 5512  
Ph. 651-452-7180

This document governs the privacy policy of our website [www.esslinger.com](http://www.esslinger.com/). Our privacy policy tells you what Personally Identifiable Information (PII) and Nonpersonal Information (NPI) we may collect from you, how we collect it, how we protect it, how we may share it, how you can access and change it, and how you can limit our sharing of it. Our privacy policy also explains certain legal rights that you have about your PII. Any capitalized terms not defined herein will have the same meaning as where they are defined elsewhere on our website.

_**Topics Covered in Our Privacy Policy**_

Definitions  
Information We Collect  
Our Use of Cookies  
How Your Information Is Used  
Protecting the Privacy Rights of Third Parties  
Retaining and Destroying Your Personal Information   
Updating, Requesting, and Deletion of Your Personal Information  
Your Rights  
Revoking Your Consent and Opting Out of Sharing Your Information  
Do Not Track Settings  
Links to Other Websites  
Protecting Children’s Privacy  
Our Email Policy  
Our Security Policy  
Use of Your Credit Card  
International Data Transfers  
Changes to Our Privacy Policy

_**Definitions**_

‘Nonpersonal Information’ (NPI) is information that is in no way personally identifiable. Some NPI is obtained automatically when you access our website with a web browser. ‘Personally Identifiable Information’ (PII) is information that is not publicly displayed and that is personally identifiable to you and obtained for us to provide you with a product or service. PII may include information such as your name, email address, physical address, phone number, credit card information, and other information that you provide to us.

**_Information We Collect_**

Generally you control the amount and type of information that you provide to us when using our website. We require you to provide us with certain information to provide you with services and products. If you do not provide us with enough information, we may not be able to process your order. If you register as a user or member to use our website, you must provide PII in order for us to provide you with various features and functionality of our website. We collect your PII in the following ways: 

#### Automatic Information

We automatically receive information from your web browser or mobile device. This information includes the name of the website from which you entered our website, if any, as well as the name of the website to which you’ll go when you leave our website. This information also includes the IP address of your computer/proxy server that you use to access the Internet, your Internet service provider’s name, web browser type, type of mobile device, and computer operating system. We use all this information to analyze trends among our users to help improve our website. 

When Entering and Using Our Website

When you enter and use our website and agree to accept cookies, some of these cookies may contain your PII.

#### At User and Member Registration

When you register as a user or member, we collect your name, email address, and other information listed.  

When Buying Products or Services

If you buy products or services from us, we collect your name, email address, physical address, credit card information, phone number, and other information listed.  

###   
Our Use of Cookies

Our website uses cookies. A cookie is a small piece of data or text file downloaded to your computer or mobile device when you access certain websites. Cookies may contain text that can be read by a web server that delivered the cookie to you. The text contained in the cookie generally consists of a sequence of letters and numbers that uniquely recognizes your computer or mobile device, but it may contain other information as well. 

By agreeing to accept our use of cookies you are giving us permission to place some or all the cookies described below on your device.

Strictly Necessary Cookies  

These cookies are necessary for proper functioning of the website such as displaying content, logging in, validating your session, responding to your request for services, and other functions. Most web browsers can be set to disable the use of cookies. However, if you disable these cookies, you may not be able to access features on our website correctly or at all. 

These cookies are always on.

Performance Cookies

These cookies collect information about the use of the website, such as pages visited, traffic sources, users’ interests, content management and other website measurements. 

Functional Cookies

These cookies let the website remember a users’ choices - such as their language, user name and other personal choices - while using the website. They can also be used to deliver services, such as letting a user make a blog post, listen to audios, or watch videos on the website.

Media Cookies 

These cookies can be used to improve a website’s performance and provide special features and content. They can be placed by third parties who provide services to us or by our company.

Advertising or Targeting Cookies 

These cookies are usually placed and used by advertising companies to develop a profile of your browsing interests and serve advertisements on other websites that are related to your interests. You will see less advertising if you disable these cookies.

Session cookies

These cookies allow websites to link the actions of a user during a browser session. They may be used for a variety of purposes such as remembering what a user has put in their shopping cart as they browse around a website. Session cookies also permit users to be recognized as they navigate a website so that any item or page changes they make are remembered from page to page. Session cookies expire after a browser session, thus are not stored long term. 

Persistent cookies  
These cookies are stored on a user’s device in between browser sessions which allow the preferences or actions of the user across a site (or in some cases across different sites) to be remembered. Persistent cookies may be used for a variety of purposes including remembering users’ choices and preferences when using a website or to target advertising to them.

We may also use cookies for:

  * Identifying the areas of our website that you have visited

  * Personalizing content that you see on our website

  * Our website analytics

  * Remarketing our products or services to you

  * Remembering your preferences, settings, and login details

  * Targeted advertising and serving ads relevant to your interests

  * Affiliate marketing

  * Allowing you to post comments

  * Allowing you to share content with social networks

Most web browsers can be set to disable the use of cookies. However, if you disable cookies, you may not be able to access features on our website correctly or at all. 

#### Web Beacons 

We may also use a technology called web beacons to collect general information about your use of our website and your use of special promotions or newsletters. The information we collect by web beacons allows us to statistically monitor the number of people who open our emails. Web beacons also help us understand the behavior of our customers and visitors. 

#### Google Ad and Content Network Privacy Policy

Third-party vendors, including Google, use cookies to serve ads based on a user's past visits to our website. Google's use of the DoubleClick cookie enables it and its partners to serve ads to our users based on their visit to our site and/or other sites on the Internet. Users may opt out of the use of the DoubleClick cookie for interest-based advertising by visiting [http://www.aboutads.info/choices/](http://www.aboutads.info/choices/)

#### Google Analytics Privacy Policy

Our website uses Google Analytics to collect information about the use of our site. Google Analytics collects information such as how often users visit our site, what pages they visit, and what other sites they used prior to coming to our site. We use the information we get from Google Analytics to improve our site. Google Analytics collects only the IP address assigned to you on the date you visit our site, not your name or other identifying information. We do not combine the information collected using Google Analytics with personally identifiable information. Although Google Analytics plants a permanent cookie on your web browser to identify you as a unique user the next time you visit our site, the cookie cannot be used by anyone but Google. You can prevent Google Analytics from using your information by opting out at this link:  [https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout)

### Google Remarketing

Our website uses a remarketing advertising service. Our remarketing service is provided by Google and other companies that show our ads on websites across the Internet. With remarketing you may see ads for our products you have previously looked at. As an example, suppose you visit a website that sells computers, but you do not buy a computer on your first visit to that website. The website’s owner might like to encourage you to revisit his site and buy a computer by showing you his ads again on other websites that you visit. We use remarketing for similar purposes. For this to happen Google will read a cookie that is already in your browser. This can only happen if your browser is set to let it happen. You can opt out of Google’s remarketing at this link:  [https://support.google.com/ads/answer/2662922?hl=en](https://support.google.com/ads/answer/2662922?hl=en)

### How Your Information Is Used

We use the information we receive from you to:

  * Provide our products and services 

  * Personalize and customize content 

  * Make improvements to our website

  * Contact you with updates to our website

  * Resolve problems and disputes

  * Contact you with marketing and advertising   
that we believe may be of interest to you.

#### Communications and emails

When we communicate with you about our website, we will use the email address you provided when registering as a member or user. We may also send you emails with promotional information about our website or offers from us or our affiliates unless you have opted out of receiving such information. You can change contact preferences at any time through your account or by sending us an email with your request to: mail@esslinger.com

Sharing information with affiliates and other third parties

We do not sell, rent, or otherwise provide your PII to third parties for marketing purposes.  However, we may use your nonpersonal information for data aggregation purposes which might be sold to other parties at our discretion. Any such data aggregation would not contain any of your PII. We may provide your PII to third-party service providers who we hire to provide services to us. These third-party service providers include but are not limited to: payment processors, web analytics companies (like Google Analytics), call centers, data management services, help desk providers, shopping cart and email service providers, and shipping and mailing companies.

#### Legally required releases of information

We may be legally required to disclose your PII if such disclosure is (a) required by subpoena, law, or other legal process; (b) necessary to assist law enforcement officials or government enforcement agencies; (c) necessary to investigate violations of or otherwise enforce our Legal Terms; (d) necessary to protect us from legal action or claims from third parties, including you and/or other users or members; (e) necessary to protect the legal rights, personal/real property, or personal safety of our company, users, employees, and affiliates.

#### Disclosures to successors

If our business is sold or merges in whole or in part with another business that would become responsible for providing the website to you, we retain the right to transfer your PII to the new business. The new business would retain the right to use your PII according to the terms of this privacy policy as well as to any changes to this privacy policy as instituted by the new business. 

#### Community discussion boards

Our website may offer the capability for users to communicate with each other through online community discussion boards. We donot filter or monitor what is posted on such discussion boards. If you choose to post on these discussion boards, you should use care when exposing any PII as such information is not protected by our privacy policy nor are we liable if you choose to disclose your PII through such postings.

**Protecting the privacy rights of third parties**

If any postings you make to our website contain information about third parties, you need to make sure that you have permission to include them in your posting. While we are not legally liable for the actions of our users, we will remove any postings for which we are notified that such postings violate the privacy rights of others.

**Retaining and Destroying Your Personal Information (PII)**

We retain information that we collect from you (including your PII) for only as long as we need such information for legal, business, or tax purposes. Your information may be retained in electronic form, paper form, or a combination of both. When your information is no longer needed, we will destroy, delete, or erase it.

### Updating, Requesting, and Deletion of Your Personal Information (PII)

You can update your PII using services found on our website. If no such services exist, you can contact us using the contact information found at the top of this policy and we will help you. You have the right to request and access the type of PII we have collected from you that is stored in electronic or paper format by our company. You also have the right to request that we delete any PII which we have about you. If you want access to your PII, are requesting to know what PII we have collected about you, or are requesting that we delete your PII, send us an email with your request to: mail@esslinger.comor contact us using our contact information at the top of this website and we will help you. However, we may keep your PII as needed to enforce our agreements and to comply with any legal obligations.

**Your Rights**

You have the right to file a complaint with supervisory authorities if your information has not been processed in compliance with the General Data Protection Regulation. If the supervisory authorities fail to address your complaint properly, you have the right to a judicial remedy.

You have the right at any time to withdraw your consent for us to use, process, and store your PII.

### Revoking Your Consent and Opting Out of Sharing Your Information 

You have the right to revoke your consent for us to use your personal information at any time.

You can always opt out of future unaffiliated third-party disclosures of your information. Such optout will not affect disclosures otherwise permitted by law including but not limited to: (i) disclosures to affiliates, (ii) disclosures to third-party service providers who provide certain services for our business, such as credit card processing, computer system services, shipping, data management, or promotional services, (iii) disclosures to third parties as necessary to fulfill your requests, (iv) disclosures to governmental agencies, law enforcement departments, or otherwise required to be made under applicable law, (v) previously completed disclosures to third parties, or (vi) disclosures to third parties in connection with subsequent contests or promotions that you may choose to enter, or third-party offers which you may choose to accept. If you want to opt out of unaffiliated third-party disclosures or revoke your consent for us to use your personal information, send us an email with your request to: mail@esslinger.com

### Do Not Track Settings

Some web browsers have settings that enable you to request that our website does not track your movement within our website. Our website does notobey such settings when transmitted to and detected by our website. You can turn off tracking features and other security settings in your browser by referring to your browser’s user manual.

### Links to Other Websites

Our website may contain links to other websites. These websites are not under our control and are not subject to our privacy policy. These websites will likely have their own privacy policies. We have no responsibility for these websites and provide links to these websites solely for your convenience. You acknowledge that your use of and access to these websites are solely at your risk. It is your responsibility to check the privacy policies of these websites to see how they treat your personal information. 

### Protecting Children’s Privacy

Even though our website is not designed for use by anyone under the age of 13 (child), we realize that a child under the age of 13 may attempt to access our website. We do not knowingly collect PII from children under the age of 13. If you are a parent or guardian and believe that your child is using our website, please contact us. We may ask for proof of identification before we remove any information to prevent malicious removal of account information. If we discover that a child is accessing our website, we will delete his/her information within a reasonable period of time. You acknowledge that we do not verify the age of our users nor have any liability to do so. 

### Our Email Policy

You can always opt out of receipt of further email correspondence from us or our affiliates. We will not sell, rent, or trade your email address to any unaffiliated third party without your permission except in the sale or transfer of our business.

### Our Security Policy

We have taken steps to build our website using industry-standard encryption and authentication tools to protect the security of your PII. When we collect your PII through our website, we will encrypt your PII before it travels over the Internet using industry-standard technology for conducting secure online transactions. We also use technologies such as secure routers and firewalls to help protect your PII. Unfortunately we cannot guarantee against the loss or misuse of your PII or secure data transmission over the Internet because of its nature.    
We strongly urge you to protect any password you may have for our website and not share it with anyone. You should always log out of our website when you finish using it, especially if you are sharing or using a computer in a public place.

### Use of Your Credit Card

You may have to provide a credit card to buy products and services from our website. We use third-party billing services and have no control over these services. We use our commercially reasonable efforts to make sure that your credit card number is kept strictly confidential by using only third-party billing services that use industry-standard encryption technology to protect your credit card number from unauthorized use. However, you understand and agree that we are in no way responsible for any misuse of your credit card number. 

International Data Transfers 

Information that we collect may be stored and processed in and transferred between any of the countries in which we operate in order to enable us to use the information in accordance with this policy. Personal information that you publish on our website or submit for publication on our website may be available via the Internet around the world. We cannot prevent the (mis)use of such information by others. You hereby agree to the transfers of personal information described within this section.

### Changes to Our Privacy Policy

We reserve the right to change this privacy policy at any time. If our company decides to change this privacy policy, we will post those changes on our website so that our users and customers are always aware of what information we collect, use, and disclose. If at any time we decide to disclose or use your PII in a method different from that specified at the time when it was collected, we will provide advance notice by email (sent to the email address on file in your account). Otherwise we will use and disclose our users’ and customers’ PII in agreement with the privacy policy that was in effect when their information was collected. In all cases your continued use of our website, services, and products after any change to this privacy policy will constitute your acceptance of such change.

### Questions About Our Privacy Policy

If you have any questions about our privacy policy, please email us at: mail@esslinger.com
